Guide to the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, UPG Staff Association, 1990-2016 UPG.RG.40
ULS Greensburg
University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, UPG Staff Association
1990-2016
ULS Greensburg
University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
UPG.RG.40
3 boxes
Administrative Records of the UPG Staff Association of the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, 1990-2016.
Access Restrictions
Restritcted Access. Series III.
Custodial History
Transferred from the UPG Staff Association to the UPG Archives.
Scope and Content Notes
By-laws, Elections, Officers, Minutes, Committees, Financial Reports, Memoranda, Report to the Advisory Board of UPG, News Releases, News Clippings
See Also
See also, UPG Archives UPG.RG.60 DVD [DVD+R]23, Retrospective 30 June (2012) Retirees.
Universities and colleges –- Pennsylvania –- Greensburg –- Records and correspondence; Universities and colleges -– Pennsylvania -– Greensburg -– Administration; University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
- Staff Concerns Committee, 1998-1999; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Committee appointed in 1998 by Dr. Frank A. Cassell, President of UPG, to determine UPG staff interest in a [staff] association, formulating tentative by-laws, seeking staff support, and organizing the initial election of officers which took place in early 1999. Original members of the committee were: Joyce Bucchi, Karen Antoniak, Gerry Enlow, and Karen Gavula.
  File contains: Dec. 11, 1998, call for a Staff Association Meeting at which a working draft of the Staff Association's By-laws was to be discussed; partial responses to a Staff Concerns Questionnaire; memo dtd 3/22/99 from Dr. Frank A. Cassell, in re the election of UPG Staff Association officers.
  - Staff Concerns Committee, 1998-1999 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 4)
- By-laws, 1998-2004; II.
  Includes: Working Draft, 12/4/98; Draft, 2/4/99; Memo dtd. 11/12/04 from Tom Horan to Karen Gavula in re "changing the By-laws to make the length of office two years instead of one"; University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Staff Association By-Laws, Dec. 15, 2004.
  - By-laws, 1998-2004 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 4)
- Elections, 1999/2000-2006/2007; III.
  Access Restrictions
  Restricted Access. [Access restricted to UPG Administrative Personnel.]
  Contains: nomination forms; forms for individuals nominated to accept or decline the nominations; specimen election ballots; election results; rosters of UPG Non-Union Staff.
  - Elections, 1999/2000-2006/2007 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 4)
- Officers, 1999-2010; IV.
  1999/2000
  President: Michele Tracy; Vice President: Tanya Conde; Treasurer: Suzanne Dominick; Secretary: Karen Mays
  2000/2001
  President: Brandi Darr Vice President: Nancy Young Treasurer: Ronna Colland Secretary: Donna Henry
  2001/2002
  President: Brandi Darr Vice President: Nancy Young Treasurer: Ronna Colland Secretary: Donna Henry Cuneo
  2002/2003
  President: Rebecca Sorice Vice President: Tom Horan Treasurer: Cindy Crosby Secretary: Debbie Kolar
  2003/2004
  President: Brandi Darr Vice President: Cheryl De Paolis Treasurer: Karen Gavula Secretary: Nancy Young
  2004/2005
  President: Tom Horan Vice President: Bryan Valentine Treasurer: Karen Gavula Secretary: Bonnie Schober
  2005/2006
  President: Tom Horan Vice President: Kathleen Murray Treasurer: Bryan Valentine Secretary: Bonnie Schober
  2006/2007
  President: Tom Horan Vice President: Sheila Confer Treasurer: Linda Soltis Secretary: Karen Gavula
  2007/2008
  President: Tom Horan Vice President: Sheila Confer Treasurer: Ronna Colland Secretary: Karen Gavula
  2008/2009
  President: Brandi Darr Vice President: Sheila Confer Treasurer: Ronna Colland Secretary: Brian Root
  2009/2010
  President: Brandi Darr Vice President: Michele Shuey Treasurer: Jan Strittmatter Secretary: Alicia Davin
  - Officers, 1999-2010 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 4)
- Minutes of UPG Staff Association Meetings, 1999-2016; V.
  1999/2000-Dec. 2007, Feb. 6, 2008, Oct. 7, 2009., Feb. 7, 2013, Sept. 15, 2016 [Meeting Agenda]
  Includes notices of meetings, agendas, minutes of meetings; University Times story of Pitt Staff Assoc. All-Campus Meeting 6/11/09, "Campus Staff Leaders: Morale a concern."
  - Minutes of UPG Staff Association Meetings, 1999-2016 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 4)
- Activities Committee, 1990-2012; VI.
  - Minutes, Feb.9, 2001; 1.
    - Minutes, Feb.9, 2001 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 4)
  - Activities, projects, 1990-2012; 2.
    American Heart Association, 2001, 2005-06, 2007
    Anniversary (UPG), 40th, 2003-2004
    Antique Car Events, 2005
    Brown Bag Luncheon, 2004-2005
    Calloway, Carol. Retirement Party (June 25, 2008)
    File Contains: minutes of committee meetings; committee correspondence; invitations; certificate of appreciation; PowerPoint Presentation; photo disc ID of individuals; expenses; maintenance requests.
    Care Package Drive, 2003 [conducted for UPG student, Marine Lance Corporal James R. Preisach. Folder includes ltr of thanks and appreciation from JRP to Dr. Frank Cassell in which JRP comments on his change of opinion about the war in Iraq.]
    Cookbook [UPG Community Cookbook] 1999-2000
    Chartwell's Appreciation Luncheon, May 2004-Aug. 2005
    Formal Garden Project, June 2001-Jan. 2002, May 2005
    Greensburg Care Center, 2003-2004
    "Pitt Pat" Award Program 1998-2000
    Salvation Army, Nov. 2000-2003 [Thanksgiving Food Baskets, Easter Food Baskets.]
    Spring Carnival, 2001
    Staff Association Council, University of Pittsburgh, Oakland Campus. 1999, 2004-2005
    Staff Classification System, Univ. of Pgh. Rev. 1999
    Staff Handbook, Univ. of Pittsburgh. January, 1990
    Staff Picnic, 2001, 2003, 2006
    Various:
    Album [UPG Staff Association Album] 2000
    Helen Connor Retirement Reception, 2002
    Creative Memoirs, 2002
    Funny Bone Comedy Club
    Greensburg Holiday Parade, 2001
    Groundhog Day Potluck Luncheon, 2005
    Halloween 2000
    ID Cards [Pitt New ID Cards] 2000
    Mums Sale, 2001
    Overly's Country Christmas, 2003
    Paper Recycling Project
    Pitt Fest 2001
    Pittsburgh Pirates Baseball Outing, 2005
    Random Act of Kindness Week, 2001
    Regional Council of Campuses (1999-2000)
    Cathy and Dave Schmitt Retirement Reception, 2004
    Staff Association Survey, 2006
    Staff Development (2006)
    Staff Benefits, Discounts, Services [UPG Employees 2002
    Staff Spirit Day, 2001
    Staff Wellness Fair (2000)
    Thanksgiving (2000)
    Valentine's Day Lottery Bowl, 2003
    Walk of Honor, 2003
    File folder also includes two memoranda: 10/1/01, thank you for supporting UPG Staff Assoc. Activities its fundraising activities (contributions included $100 to the Juvenile Diabetes Walk, 9/22/02; $100 to the Tosatto Memorial Scholarship Endowment; $100 to the Rossetti International Study Endowment; approximately $260 to the Make-A-Wish Project)
    Memo 11/19/01 in re Candy Bar Sale ($500 donated to the Attack on America Fund)
    Greensburg Annual Holiday Parade, 2001
    Judicial Appeals Committee seeking 3 staff members to form a standing committee
    Memorandum dtd 12/17/01 from UPG Staff Assoc. Issues and Concerns Committee and UPG Off. of Human Resources to Dr. Frank Cassell. Subj.: Waiver of Part-time Fees [for UPG Staff members who are also part time UPG students]
    Card of thanks (undtd) from New Beginnings clubhouse, West Place Drop In Center
    June 30, 2012 Retirerees Retirement Reception (June 15, 2012)
    See Also
    See also, UPG Archives UPG.RG.60 DVD [DVD+R]23, Retrospective 30 June (2012) Retirees.]
    - Activities, projects, 1990-2012 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 4, Box 5)
- Communications Committee, 2001; VII.
  File contains: Memo 1/3/01 in re process for sending/distributing Staff Assoc. announcements, minutes of meetings, etc.; draft dtd 1/31/01 of Communications Committee Mission Statement; e-mail dtd 2/23/01 from Karen Antoniak in reply to Karen Gavula's request for "kind of information" is given to new employees; agenda for Communications Committee mtng of 2/27/01.
  - Communications Committee, 2001 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 6)
- Financial Reports, 1999/2000-2003/2004; VIII.
  - Financial Reports, 1999/2000-2003/2004 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 6)
- Memoranda, 2003-2005; IX.
  Includes: Summary of individual pay relative to the maximum of a range for Univ. of Pgh. Classified employees, rev. 2/12/03; 5/14/2003 from Joyce Bucchi, subject "University Staff Handbook Updates (1) Use of Sick Time and FMLA and (2) Disciplinary Guidelines; memo dtd 9/22/03 from Dr. Cassell to Brandi Darr, subject, "Staff Participation in Campus Events"; completed copy of Sarbanese-Oxley Act of 2002 Questionnaire 7/18/05 [signed certification that financial statements are free of material misstatements or omissions].
  - Memoranda, 2003-2005 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 6)
- Report to the Advisory Board of UPG, 2002-2004, 2006; X.
  - Report to the Advisory Board of UPG, 2002-2004, 2006 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 6)
- News Releases, 2003-2005; XI.
  [11-12-03] [Subject: Review of UPG Staff Association activities during 2003/04] Sent for inclusion in [University of Pittsburgh] SAC Newsletter. [2-19-04] [Subject: Review of UPG Staff Association activities during 2004/05]
  - News Releases, 2003-2005 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 6)
- News Clippings, 2001-2007; XII.
  3/22/01, 3/15/03, 6/24/04, 5/31/07
  - News Clippings, 2001-2007 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 10, Box 6)